Guide to the Peter Gregg Papers, 1937-1995 CTC.1979.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Peter Gregg Papers
1937-1995
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Gregg, Peter
CTC.1979.01
3 Linear Feet
Peter Gregg was a Pittsburgh area actor and playwright. This collection includes his play scripts, correspondence, memorabilia, employment records, book reviews, and photographs.
Scope and Content Notes
This collection contains the papers of actor and playwright Peter Gregg. It includes play scripts, correspondence, book reviews, photographs, and a scrapbook. Also included are a sampling of Mr. Gregg's business contracts and copyrights. The materials date from the 1930s through the 1990s.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Peter Gregg in 1979, additional materials were donated in 1982.
Biography
Playwright and former actor, Peter Gregg, born Joseph Peter Crocco, is a native of western Pennsylvania. He began his theatrical career at the Carnegie Institute of Technology, where he was enrolled in the Drama Department from 1934 to 1937.
Mr. Gregg moved to New York in 1937 and won his first professional part a year later in Cry for Passion, an off-Broadway production. He continued to work off-Broadway for the next few years both as an actor and stage manager. In 1941, he earned a part in the successful Broadway play The Doughgirls, produced by Max Gordon and George S. Kaufman, and he later served as a stage manager, director, and actor in The Doughgirls touring company. After World War II, Mr. Gregg returned to the New York stage, and for the next nine years, he worked in theater, radio, and films. He gave up his pursuit of an acting career in 1954 when he returned to Pittsburgh.
Mr. Gregg wrote his first play, Sweet Delirium, in 1946. It was seriously considered for production by Forest Haring but was eventually dropped. Some years later, Mr. Gregg sold another play to Broadway producers, but it was also not produced. He continued to write plays until his death.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Previous Citation
Peter Gregg Papers, 1937-1995, CTC.1979.01, Curtis Theatre Collection, Special Collections Department, University of Pittsburgh
Peter Gregg Papers, 1937-1995, CTC.14, Curtis Theatre Collection, Special Collections Department, University of Pittsburgh
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in the following series:
Series I. Play Scripts and Plot Synopses
Series II. Correspondence, 1946-1995
Series III. Book Reviews, 1961-1974
Series IV. Legal Documents and Miscellaneous Memorabilia
Performing arts -- United States; Theater -- United States; Actors and actresses; Dramatists; Legal documents; Theater; Personal papers; Scrapbooks; Scripts (Documents); Reviews (Document genre); Photographs; Correspondence; Carnegie Institute of Technology. Department of Drama; Kaufman, George S. (George Simon) -- Correspondence; Gregg, Peter
- Play Scripts and Plot Synopses, I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  Within this series are eight typed play scripts, three synopses, and three ideas for television productions. Some folders contain lists of persons for whom plays were sent for consideration. In one case, there is only a list of persons to whom the script was sent.
  - Ad Cats and Goose Liver (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Apollo Wears a Davy Lamp (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bard from Ludlow - final copy (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
  - Bard from Ludlow - Act I version one draft (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Bard from Ludlow - Act I version two draft (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Bard from Ludlow - Acts II and III drafts (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Bard from Ludlow - miscellaneous pages (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Bard from Ludlow - preface (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Bard from Ludlow - notes (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Bring in Blotz - script (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Fatal Haircut - T.V. idea (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Guess the Address - synopsis (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Holiday for Mary - script (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Innocent Wine - script (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Matches That Matched - T.V. idea (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Of Thee We Sing - synopsis (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Operation Vacation - script (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Operation Vacation - rewrites (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Playboy Blue - script (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Sweet Delirium - script (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - This Day's Madness - submission list only (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Those Who Made History Meet Their Critics - T.V. idea (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Whose Tomorrow - script (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous - entitled (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous notes (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, 1946-1995; II.
  This series of correspondence contains both personal and work related materials. The folders that are labeled miscellaneous incoming letters are mainly letters that relate to Gregg's play scripts, replies from agencies and persons to whom he sent scripts for consideration. There is also a large amount of correspondence with friend Stephen Radkey. Finally, there is one folder each of letters from George S. Kaufman, copies of outgoing letters, and letters about the Bard from Ludlow.
  - Letters from George S. Kaufman (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous incoming letters, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous incoming letters, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous incoming letters, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous incoming letters, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous incoming letters, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous incoming letters, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous incoming letters, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous incoming letters, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous incoming letters, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous incoming letters, 1957-1978 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous incoming letters - no dates (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Incoming letters from Stephen Radkey, 1974-1980 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Incoming letters from Stephen Radkey, 1980-1985 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Incoming letters from Stephen Radkey, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Incoming letters from Stephen Radkey, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Incoming letters from Stephen Radkey, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Incoming letters from Stephen Radkey, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Incoming letters from Stephen Radkey, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Incoming letters from Stephen Radkey, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Incoming letters from Stephen Radkey, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Incoming letters from Stephen Radkey, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Incoming letters from Stephen Radkey, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Incoming letters from Stephen Radkey, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Incoming letters from Stephen Radkey - no dates (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Incoming correspondence concerning Bard from Ludlow (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Outgoing letters, 1946-1995 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Book Reviews, 1961-1974; III.
  These reviews were published in the Sunday edition of the Pittsburgh Press, and are mainly of books about theater but include some contemporary fiction and literary criticism. The original clippings have been xeroxed.
  - Book reviews, 1961-1965 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Book reviews, 1966-1974 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Book reviews - no dates (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Legal Documents and Miscellaneous Materials, IV.
  Series includes legal materials, employment records, photographs, etc. The scrapbook covers Peter Gregg's acting career. It includes Carnegie Tech, Off-Broadway, and Broadway programs, photographs, Equity Contracts, clippings, etc. Also contains several Pittsburgh articles that summarize Gregg's years in New York. There are two tape recordings of a Pittsburgh Ad Club production, Ad Cats and Goose Livers, written by Mr. Gregg. Also includes programs from the Ad Club, Lemonade Opera, and some material relating to Mr. Gregg's radio days. There are several newsletters and other publications from the Dramatist's Guild, The Lions Club of Pittsburgh, and the Pittsburgh Ad Club.
  - Personal history and resumes (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Copyrights, 1946-1950 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Theatrical contracts, 1947-1953 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Employment records, 1946-1954 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Photographs (Box 6, Folder 5)
    The photographs, a gift from Lester Sweyd, include pictures of Moss Hart and Cary Grant. In addition, there are photos of Greg, himself, as well as three strips of negatives.
  - Scrapbook, 1943-1957 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Audio recordings of Ad Club Shows (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Kenny and Penny milk commercial (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Newspaper clippings, newsletters, etc., 1950-1993 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Comedy and Tragedy plaster wall masks (Box 7, Folder 1)